QUESTIONS = [
  {
    "question": "A topic sentence usually relates to the central theme of the _____________",
    "options": {
      "A": "Write up",
      "B": "essay",
      "C": "report",
      "D": "paragraph"
    },
    "answer": "D",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "The only way you can learn how to summarise a given passage is for you to ______",
    "options": {
      "A": "listen carefully to a summary lecture",
      "B": "Stylishly copy your colleague\u2019s work when no one is watching",
      "C": "do it practically",
      "D": "learn it off-hand"
    },
    "answer": "C",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "Even if you are confident and experienced, you must remember that ______is the first step towards success at an interview.",
    "options": {
      "A": "gathering relevant documents together",
      "B": "preparation",
      "C": "arriving at the interview venue on time.",
      "D": "memorising important information relevant to the interview"
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "'Piranhas comprise more than 30-60 species of fish, which fall into four general types: Pygocentrus, Pygopristis, Serrasalmus, and Pristobrycon' is an example of one of the following ______",
    "options": {
      "A": "identification",
      "B": "description",
      "C": "explanation",
      "D": "definition"
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "Beginning a paragraph with ________ helps both the reader and the writer understand clearly what the paragraph is abou",
    "options": {
      "A": "Generalisations",
      "B": "examples",
      "C": "illustrations",
      "D": "a topic sentence"
    },
    "answer": "D",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "Explaining ________ of a concept or thing is called definition.",
    "options": {
      "A": "the make up",
      "B": "the illustration",
      "C": "the context",
      "D": "the meaning"
    },
    "answer": "D",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "_________ is the logical transition from one idea to the next in a given paragraph.",
    "options": {
      "A": "Transition",
      "B": "Cohesion",
      "C": "Linguistic expression",
      "D": "Logical movement"
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "________in a piece of writing refers to the logical transition from one idea to the next.",
    "options": {
      "A": "Coherence",
      "B": "Practical transition",
      "C": "Gradual transition",
      "D": "Critical transition"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "_______ are often unified by a central theme.",
    "options": {
      "A": "Similar phrases in a given sentence",
      "B": "Different sentence structures",
      "C": "Different paragraphs",
      "D": "Different clause patterns in a sentence"
    },
    "answer": "C",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "The main idea is usually couched in the",
    "answer": "Topic sentence",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "Most topic sentences are usually ______ of the paragraph",
    "answer": "at the beginning ",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "In most writings, the _____ in a paragraph tends to present the central theme in it.",
    "answer": "first sentence",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "The central concern of narrative writing is",
    "answer": "telling a story",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "__________which are said in a warm friendly way should always be said with the rising tone.",
    "options": {
      "A": "Formal requests",
      "B": "Refusal of requests",
      "C": "Allegations",
      "D": "Wh-questions"
    },
    "answer": "D",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "It has been observed that students who want to be __________, need to learn how to summarise.",
    "options": {
      "A": "well-grounded in the act of plagiarism",
      "B": "well-grounded in their speaking skills",
      "C": "well-focused in their writing",
      "D": "excellent in their debating skills"
    },
    "answer": "C",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "In every piece of writing, the ________should relate to the central theme of the paragraph.",
    "options": {
      "A": "Supporting ideas",
      "B": "Main points",
      "C": "Relevant issues",
      "D": "topic sentence"
    },
    "answer": "D",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "The _________, 'Piranhas attack larger animals only when they are wounded. The presence of blood in the water may tempt the fish to attack', is an example of an explanation.",
    "options": {
      "A": "illustration",
      "B": "description",
      "C": "Caption",
      "D": "statement"
    },
    "answer": "D",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "Placing a topic sentence at the end of a paragraph _________",
    "options": {
      "A": "helps both the reader and the writer",
      "B": "allows for an effective summary",
      "C": "allows for all the sentences to be built up to the topic",
      "D": "makes the paragraph more effective"
    },
    "answer": "C",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "It is a grammatical fact that a topic sentence cannot be _________.",
    "options": {
      "A": "a statement",
      "B": "An interrogative utterance",
      "C": "Complex-compound sentence",
      "D": "Complex sentence"
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "The word DEFINITION can mean ____________________",
    "options": {
      "A": "analysing the meaning of a concept or thing",
      "B": "explaining the meaning of a concept or thing",
      "C": "identifying the meaning of a concept or thing",
      "D": "illustrating the meaning of a concept or thing"
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "Expressions like 'first, second, third, ' indicate _________within sentences",
    "options": {
      "A": "sequence",
      "B": "comparison",
      "C": "result",
      "D": "contrast"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "One of the following words or phrases expresses additional information__________",
    "options": {
      "A": "besides",
      "B": "likewise",
      "C": "consequently",
      "D": "next"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "The main idea is usually couched in the",
    "answer": "Topic sentence",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "The topic sentence in a paragraph often leads to the achievement of ______ in the given composition itself.",
    "options": {
      "A": "transitional devices",
      "B": "logical transitions",
      "C": "coherence",
      "D": "supporting details"
    },
    "answer": "C",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "When writing, which of the following may not help you achieve coherence in your paragraphs?_______",
    "options": {
      "A": "Transitional devices",
      "B": "Logical transitions",
      "C": "Topic sentence and supporting details",
      "D": "topic sentence"
    },
    "answer": "C",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "As far as the topic sentence is concerned, there is often more than one in a paragraph. This sentence is _______________",
    "options": {
      "A": "probable",
      "B": "Very likely, but it depends on the paragraph structure",
      "C": "Right and can be proved",
      "D": "Wrong and cannot be ascertained"
    },
    "answer": "D",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "The word dancing in \u201cDancing is fun\u201d is a _____.",
    "answer": "gerund",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "Modal auxiliaries like can, may, must, and should express various shades of _____.",
    "answer": "meaning",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "The sentences that explain or support the topic sentence are called _____ sentences.",
    "answer": "supporting",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "Words or phrases that connect ideas smoothly in writing are called _____.",
    "answer": "transitional devices",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "Giving examples to explain a point is known as the method of paragraph development by _____.",
    "answer": "illustration",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "Writing that paints a picture in the reader\u2019s mind is paragraph development by _____.",
    "answer": "description",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "Paragraphs can also be developed by showing causes and _____.",
    "answer": "effects",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "When two ideas or objects are examined for similarities, the method used is _____.",
    "answer": "comparison",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "Placing a topic sentence at the end of a paragraph ________",
    "options": {
      "A": "allows for all the sentences to be built up to the topic",
      "B": "helps both the reader and the writer",
      "C": "makes the paragraph more effective",
      "D": "allows for an effective summary"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "The word \u2018however\u2019 is often used in a write up to express ________",
    "options": {
      "A": "functionality",
      "B": "consequences",
      "C": "contrast",
      "D": "continuity"
    },
    "answer": "C",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "_________ is a phrase that helps the writer to express result in a writing",
    "options": {
      "A": "Similarly",
      "B": "Accordingly",
      "C": "Yet",
      "D": "Furthermore"
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "The sentence \u201cOn the contrary, I see the idea as one that will divide us\u201d expresses _______",
    "options": {
      "A": "a temporal relationship",
      "B": "Idealistic issues",
      "C": "a contrast",
      "D": "The sense of sight"
    },
    "answer": "C",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "The word \u2018besides\u2019 can be used to express ________ in a write up.",
    "options": {
      "A": "additional information",
      "B": "Synonymous information",
      "C": "The first piece of information",
      "D": "Opposing information"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "___________in paragraphs help the reader to understand difficult concepts presented in the composition",
    "options": {
      "A": "Metaphorical expressions",
      "B": "Contextual expressions",
      "C": "Ironical expressions",
      "D": "Illustrations"
    },
    "answer": "D",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "The vowel /\u026a\u0259/ in \u201chere\u201d is a type of _____.",
    "answer": "diphthong",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "The pattern of pitch changes that convey meaning in speech is called _____.",
    "answer": "intonation",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "The rising intonation pattern often indicates a _____ question.",
    "answer": "yes/no",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "In interview preparation, candidates should research the organization and review their _____.",
    "answer": "curriculum vitae (CV)",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "One major type of interview conducted for academic purposes is the _____ interview.",
    "answer": "oral",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "During an interview, good posture and proper eye contact communicate _____.",
    "answer": "confidence",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "In a seminar presentation, visuals such as slides or charts help to enhance _____.",
    "answer": "clarity",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "The tone, pitch, and volume of a speaker\u2019s voice contribute to his or her speech _____.",
    "answer": "delivery",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "The fear of speaking before an audience is known as _____.",
    "answer": "stage fright",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "The words a, an, and the are known as _____.",
    "answer": "articles",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "A and an are called _____ articles.",
    "answer": "indefinite",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "The agreement between a subject and its verb in number and person is called _____.",
    "answer": "concord",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "A sentence that makes a statement is a _____ sentence.",
    "answer": "declarative",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is NOT a reason for comparison and contrast in paragraph development? _________",
    "options": {
      "A": "to show the superiority of one thing over another",
      "B": "to identify issues in paragraphs",
      "C": "to point out distinctions when giving information on two things",
      "D": "to clarify the unfamiliar by comparing it with the familiar"
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "The word \u2018subsequently\u2019 can be used to express ________ in a write up.",
    "options": {
      "A": "Consequential actions",
      "B": "time",
      "C": "Nonsensical expressions",
      "D": "Idiomatic usage"
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "The topic sentence in a paragraph often leads to the achievement of ______ in the given composition itself.",
    "options": {
      "A": "coherence",
      "B": "supporting details",
      "C": "transitional devices",
      "D": "logical transitions"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "Beginning a paragraph with ________ helps both the reader and the writer understand clearly what the paragraph is about",
    "options": {
      "A": "a topic sentence",
      "B": "illustrations",
      "C": "examples",
      "D": "Generalisations"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "'On the contrary\u00a0I see the idea as one that will divide us'. The underlined word in the sentence indicates _____",
    "options": {
      "A": "a contrast",
      "B": "a comparison",
      "C": "an example",
      "D": "a temporal relationship"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "The core aspect of a paragraph is its",
    "answer": "Main idea",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "Most topic sentences are usually ______ of the paragraph",
    "answer": "at the beginning ",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "In most writings, the _____ in a paragraph tends to present the central theme in it.",
    "answer": "first sentence",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "The central concern of narrative writing is",
    "answer": "telling a story",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "An essay you write to present your class debate will be written in _____ language.",
    "answer": "formal",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "Most letters to the editor tend to contain",
    "answer": "complaints",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "If you witnessed an armed robbery incident, the report you will give to the Police is called",
    "answer": "a statement",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "English speech sounds are divided into _____ and consonants.",
    "answer": "vowels",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "Expressions like 'first, second, third, ' indicate _________within sentences in a given paragraph.",
    "options": {
      "A": "sequence",
      "B": "result",
      "C": "comparison",
      "D": "contrast"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "The word \u2018accordingly\u2019 is used in an essay to express ________",
    "options": {
      "A": "continuity",
      "B": "result",
      "C": "opposition",
      "D": "similarity"
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "The word ___________ is often used to express time in a given composition.",
    "options": {
      "A": "consequently",
      "B": "subsequently",
      "C": "hence",
      "D": "finally"
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "_________ is a phrase that helps the writer to express result in a writing",
    "options": {
      "A": "Yet",
      "B": "Furthermore",
      "C": "Similarly",
      "D": "Accordingly"
    },
    "answer": "D",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "_________ is the form of speech we use with close associates and people of equal status.",
    "options": {
      "A": "Informal language",
      "B": "Formal language",
      "C": "Legal language",
      "D": "Colloquial language"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "The physical act of producing speech is called _____.",
    "answer": "articulation",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "The two main kinds of participles are the _____ and the past participle.",
    "answer": "present participle",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "The word dancing in \u201cDancing is fun\u201d is a _____.",
    "answer": "gerund",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "Modal auxiliaries like can, may, must, and should express various shades of _____.",
    "answer": "meaning",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "The sentences that explain or support the topic sentence are called _____ sentences.",
    "answer": "supporting",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "Words or phrases that connect ideas smoothly in writing are called _____.",
    "answer": "transitional devices",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "Giving examples to explain a point is known as the method of paragraph development by _____.",
    "answer": "illustration",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "Writing that paints a picture in the reader\u2019s mind is paragraph development by _____.",
    "answer": "description",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "Paragraphs can also be developed by showing causes and _____.",
    "answer": "effects",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "When two ideas or objects are examined for similarities, the method used is _____.",
    "answer": "comparison",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "__________are usually not written when one is requesting acquaintance.",
    "options": {
      "A": "Letters requesting information",
      "B": "Business letters",
      "C": "Letters requesting actions",
      "D": "Informal letters"
    },
    "answer": "D",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "'I write on behalf of the company's management board to offer you an appointment' is introductory statement of a _____",
    "options": {
      "A": "Letter of request",
      "B": "letter of offer",
      "C": "Private letter",
      "D": "letter of complaint"
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following statements is NOT correct about writing reports of experiments?____",
    "options": {
      "A": "The report should be clear, brief and to the point",
      "B": "It should avoid ambiguous statements",
      "C": "The report should follow a logical order",
      "D": "The report should be informal and private"
    },
    "answer": "D",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "One of the following is the most appropriate way to request for an interview _____",
    "options": {
      "A": "i will be happy to attend an interview if you will give me the chance",
      "B": "I will be available for an interview at your earliest convenience",
      "C": "'I hope and pray that you will grant me an interview'",
      "D": "I am expecting your response and an interview date"
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "___________ is NOT usually used in descriptive writing.",
    "options": {
      "A": "Shapes and patterns",
      "B": "Place and position; direction",
      "C": "Measurements: weight, size, volume, distance",
      "D": "Temporal issues"
    },
    "answer": "D",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "Writers are often encouraged to use adequate illustrations in paragraphs because they ___",
    "options": {
      "A": "help both writer and reader understand each other",
      "B": "help the writer to create an accurate image of an event",
      "C": "help the reader to understand difficult concepts",
      "D": "help the writer to explain reasons for an event"
    },
    "answer": "C",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the sentence, 'She was always out of school during the weekends in her undergraduate days' the tense form used is_______",
    "options": {
      "A": "past continuous",
      "B": "simple past tense",
      "C": "past tense",
      "D": "simple tense"
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "It is often recommended that writers use descriptions in paragraphs because they _____",
    "options": {
      "A": "help the writer to create an accurate image of an event",
      "B": "the writer to explain reasons for an event",
      "C": "help both writer and reader appreciates the issues discussed in the paragraph",
      "D": "help the reader to understand difficult concepts"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which vowel is represented in the word 'bead'? ________",
    "options": {
      "A": "/e/",
      "B": "/ee/",
      "C": "/ei/",
      "D": "/I:/"
    },
    "answer": "D",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which is the appropriate present perfect tense form needed to complete the sentence 'The fishermen _______ fishing all night long'?",
    "options": {
      "A": "have been",
      "B": "would have been",
      "C": "could have been",
      "D": "Should have been"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "A good summary should be brief, clear, and free from _____.",
    "answer": "personal opinion",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "The English sound system is made up of about _____ speech sounds.",
    "answer": 44,
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "The study of speech sounds in a language is known as _____.",
    "answer": "phonetics",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "The study of how sounds function and pattern in a language is called _____.",
    "answer": "phonology",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "Sounds that are produced in almost the same way but differ slightly are called _____.",
    "answer": "allophones",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "The vibration of the vocal cords in sound production determines whether a sound is _____ or voiceless.",
    "answer": "voiced",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "The organs of speech include the lips, teeth, tongue, alveolar ridge, and _____.",
    "answer": "vocal cords",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "The air that produces speech comes from the _____.",
    "answer": "lungs",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "The sound /\u0283/ in \u201cship\u201d is an example of a _____.",
    "answer": "voiceless fricative",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "The vowel sounds /i\u02d0/ and /\u026a/ differ mainly in _____.",
    "answer": "length",
    "type": "fill"
  }
]